@jgoley (803) 767-3375 JGoley@gmail.com jonathangoley.com | github.com/jgoley

# PERSONAL STATEMENT

A team player who possesses both the analytical mind of a programmer and the creativity of an artist. Jonathan has over 8 years of work experience in the non-profit sector where he refined skills in web development, multimedia production and project management. He seeks work opportunities that inspire creative expression and growth.

## **KEY SKILLS**

**Web development:** JavaScript (Backbone, Ember, JQuery), HTML5, CSS3 (SASS, Bourbon, Neat), PHP, MySQL,

mobile responsive development, GIT, Gulp

**Graphics/Photography:** Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Google SketchUp

Video/Audio: HDSLR video capture, Premiere, Audition

## **EDUCATION**

**The Iron Yard** | Aug - Nov 2014 Front-End Engineering

University of South Carolina | May 2005 BFA | Art Studio with a photographic concentration GPA: 3.7 (Cum Laude)

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Columbia Museum of Art | Columbia, SC | (February 2006 - present)

Web and Digital Media Consultant | (August 2014 – present)

- Execute technical changes to website
- Maintain exhibition tour application and add tour content

### Senior Digital Media Manager | (January 2014 - August 2014)

- Designed, developed and maintained the CMA website and exhibition webpages
- Created content for and developed exhibition multimedia tours
- Created multimedia content for the Museum's quarterly electronic publication
- Managed and trained multimedia production assistant
- Shot and edited video productions to market exhibitions and educate museum patrons
- Photographed events and artwork for publication
- Managed the production and installation of exhibition signage

#### Digital Media Manager | (July 2012 - December 2013)

- Created the technical infrastructure for an interpretive exhibition tour program to enhance visitor experience (tours.columbiamuseum.org)
- Created electronic versions of the Museum's quarterly publication: Collections
- Initiated an ongoing partnership with IT-oLogy to develop relationships with tech companies
- Coordinated and lead an interdepartmental web-team

### Assistant Preparator & Digital Image Technician | (October 2009 - July 2012)

- Initiated and executed a complete re-design of the Museum's website
- Optimized the Museum's digital imaging workflow

#### Assistant Preparator | (February 2006 - July 2012)

- Team-player in the installation of major exhibitions composed of 2D and 3D objects
- Used extreme care and attention to detail when preparing artwork for installation

### **HONORS AND AWARDS**

CMA Director's Award (Staff Person of the Year), 2010 Contemporaries' Artist of the Year - CMA, 2009 Eagle Scout Award, Boy Scouts of America, 1999

## **ACTIVITIES AND SERVICE**

IT-oLogy Volunteer | 2013 - present Beekeeping Mentor (MSBA) | 2013 - present Habitat for Humanity Volunteer | 2012 - present Assistant Scout Master | 2006 - 2011

